On November 5th, 1990,
في الخامس من نونبر ،سنة 1990،
a man named El-Sayyid Nosair walked
دخل رجل يدعى السيد نصير
into a hotel in Manhattan
إلى فندق في منهاتن
and assassinated Rabbi Meir Kahane,
وقتل الحاخام مير كاهان،
the leader of the Jewish Defense League.
زعيم عصبة الدفاع اليهودية.
Nosair was initially found not guilty of the murder,
لم تتم إدانة نصير بالقتل بالأساس
but while serving time on lesser charges,
لكنه حين كان يقضي مدة سجن متعلقة بقضايا أخف،
he and other men began planning attacks
كان يخطط بمعية رجال آخرين لهجمات
on a dozen New York City landmarks,
على عشرات من المواقع في مدينة نيويورك،
including tunnels, synagogues
بما في ذلك من أنفاق و معابد يهودية
and the United Nations headquarters.
و المقر الرئيسي للأمم المتحدة.
Thankfully, those plans were foiled
لحسن الحظ،تم إحباط هذه المخططات
by an FBI informant.
من طرف عميل بكمتب التحقيقات الفدرالي.
Sadly, the 1993 bombing
مع الأسف تفجير سنة 1993
of the World Trade Center was not.
للمركز التجاري العالمي لم يحبط.
Nosair would eventually be convicted
تمت إدانة نصير في النهاية
for his involvement in the plot.
لتورطه في العملية.
El-Sayyid Nosair is my father.
السيد نصير هو والدي.
I was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
ولدت في بيتسبرغ، في بنسلفانيا
in 1983 to him, an Egyptian engineer,
سنة 1983 منه، وهو مهندس مصري،
and a loving American mother and grade school teacher,
ومن أم أمريكية محبة، كانت معلمة في الصف الإبتدائي،
who together tried their best
وقد بذلا معا كل ما في وسعهما
to create a happy childhood for me.
ليجعلاني أعيش طفولة سعيدة.
It wasn't until I was seven years old
لدى بلوغي سن السابعة
that our family dynamic started to change.
بدأت حيوية عائلتنا تتغير.
My father exposed me to a side of Islam
حين عرضني أبي على جانب من الإسلام
that few people, including the majority of Muslims,
قليل من الناس، بما في ذلك غالبية المسلمين،
get to see.
لم يكونوا ليروه.
It's been my experience that when people
تقول تجربتي الخاصة أنه حين
take the time to interact with one another,
يأخذ الناس وقتهم للتواصل مع بعضهم البعض،
it doesn't take long to realize that for the most part,
لا يتطلب الأمر جهدا لكي يدركوا أنه في المجمل،
we all want the same things out of life.
نتوق جميعا لنفس الأشياء في الحياة.
However, in every religion, in every population,
لكن بالمقابل، في كل دين، وفي كل مجتمع،
you'll find a small percentage of people
ستجد فئة قليلة من الناس
who hold so fervently to their beliefs
ممن يتشبثون بحماس بمعتقداتهم
that they feel they must use any means necessary
لدرجة أنهم يشعرون بأن عليهم استعمال كل الوسائل الضرورية
to make others live as they do.
ليحملوا الآخرين على العيش كما يفعلون.
A few months prior to his arrest,
قبيل بضعة أشهر من اعتقاله،
he sat me down and explained that
أجلسني و شرح لي أنه
for the past few weekends, he and some friends
خلال عطل نهاية الأسابيع الماضية، كان وبعض من أصدقائه
had been going to a shooting range on Long Island
يذهبون لتمارين الرماية في "لونغ آيلند"
for target practice.
من أجل التمرن على الأهداف.
He told me I'd be going with him the next morning.
وقال لي أنني سأرافقه في الصباح التالي.
We arrived at Calverton Shooting Range,
وصلنا إلى ميدان الرماية "كالفيرتون"،
which unbeknownst to our group was being watched
والذي كان، بدون علم من مجموعتنا، مراقبا
by the FBI.
من طرف مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي.
When it was my turn to shoot,
حين جاء دوري لإطلاق النار،
my father helped me hold the rifle to my shoulder
ساعدني أبي على حمل البندقية على كتفي
and explained how to aim at the target
وشرح لي كيف علي أن استهدف الهدف
about 30 yards off.
على بعد 30 ياردة.
That day, the last bullet I shot
في ذلك اليوم، أصابت آخر رصاصة أطلقتها
hit the small orange light that sat on top of the target
الضوء البرتقالي الصغير الذي كان يوجد فوق الهدف
and to everyone's surprise, especially mine,
وما كان مفاجئا بالنسبة للجميع، خاصة بالنسبة لي،
the entire target burst into flames.
أن الهدف بأكمله قد انفجر مشتعلا.
My uncle turned to the other men,
التفت عمي إلى باقي الرجال،
and in Arabic said, "Ibn abuh."
فقال بالعربية ،"ابن أبيه."
Like father, like son.
ذلك الشبل من ذاك الأسد.
They all seemed to get a really big laugh out of that comment,
وعلى ما يبدو أنهم انفجروا ضاحكين على هذا التعليق،
but it wasn't until a few years later
لكن تطلب الأمر بضع سنين
that I fully understood what they thought was so funny.
لكي أفهم تماما ما الذي كانوا يعتقدون أنه طريف في الأمر.
They thought they saw in me the same destruction
لقد اعتقدوا أنهم رأوا فيَّ نفس الدمار
my father was capable of.
الذي كان والدي قادرا على فعله.
Those men would eventually be convicted
كان هؤلاء الرجال قد أدينوا بالنهاية
of placing a van filled with 1,500 pounds of explosives
بتهمة وضع شاحنة صغيرة محملة ب 1500 باوند من المتفجرات
into the sub-level parking lot of the World Trade Center's North Tower,
في الطابق تحت الأرضي لموقف سيارات تابع للبرج الشمالي لمركز التجارة العالمي،
causing an explosion that killed six people
مسببين انفجارا أدى إلى مقتل 6 أشخاص
and injured over 1,000 others.
وجرح أكثر من 1000 آخرين.
These were the men I looked up to.
كان هؤلاء الرجال قدوتي.
These were the men I called ammu, which means uncle.
كان هؤلاء من أناديهم " عمو" مما يعني "عمي".
By the time I turned 19,
حين بلغت 19 من عمري،
I had already moved 20 times in my life,
كنت قد انتقلت 20 مرة في حياتي،
and that instability during my childhood
عدم الاستقرار ذلك خلال طفولتي
didn't really provide an opportunity
لم يمنحني فعلا فرصة
to make many friends.
للتعرف على أصدقاء كثر.
Each time I would begin to feel comfortable around someone,
في كل مرة أبدأ بالشعور بالارتياح لشخص ما،
it was time to pack up and move to the next town.
تكون تلك الفترة التي عليها أن نجمع حقائبنا لننتقل للمدينة التالية.
Being the perpetual new face in class,
ولكوني دائما التلميذ الجديد في القسم،
I was frequently the target of bullies.
كنت غالبا ما أكون عرضة للمضايقات.
I kept my identity a secret from my classmates
كنت أخفي هويتي عن زملائي في القسم
to avoid being targeted,
لكي أتجنب استهدافي،
but as it turns out, being the quiet, chubby new kid in class
لكنه تبين أنه، كوني الولد الهادئ والسمين الجديد في القسم
was more than enough ammunition.
كان يشكل ذخيرة جيدة للسخرية.
So for the most part, I spent my time at home
لذا في غالب الأحيان، كنت أقضي يومي في البيت
reading books and watching TV
أطالع الكتب وأشاهد التلفاز
or playing video games.
أو ألعب ألعاب الفيديو.
For those reasons, my social skills were lacking,
ولهذه الأسباب، كنت أفتقر للمهارات الاجتماعية،
to say the least,
على أقل تقدير،
and growing up in a bigoted household,
وترعرعي في منزل متعصب،
I wasn't prepared for the real world.
لم يمكني من الاستعداد لمواجهة العالم الحقيقي.
I'd been raised to judge people
كبرت وأنا أحكم على الناس
based on arbitrary measurements,
بناء على مقاييس اعتباطية،
like a person's race or religion.
مثل عرق أو دين المرء.
So what opened my eyes?
إذن فما الذي فتح عيني؟
One of my first experiences
إحدى أولى تجاربي
that challenged this way of thinking
التي تحدت طريقة تفكيري
was during the 2000 presidential elections.
كانت خلال الانتخابات الرئاسية لسنة 2000.
Through a college prep program,
خلال برنامج إعدادي في الجامعة
I was able to take part
كنت عضوا
in the National Youth Convention in Philadelphia.
في المجلس الوطني للشباب في فيلاديلفيا.
My particular group's focus was on youth violence,
كان تركيز مجموعتي الخاصة عن عنف الشباب،
and having been the victim of bullying for most of my life,
وكوني قد كنت ضحية المضايقات معظم حياتي،
this was a subject in which I felt particularly passionate.
كان هذا موضوعا كنت متحمسا لأجله بشكل خاص.
The members of our group came from many different walks of life.
كان أعضاء المجموعة من مختلف مشارب الحياة.
One day toward the end of the convention,
في أحد الأيام، في نهاية المجلس،
I found out that one of the kids I had befriended
اكتشفت أن أحد الأطفال الذين صادقتهم
was Jewish.
كان يهوديا.
Now, it had taken several days
الآن، لقد تطلب الأمر مني عدة أيام
for this detail to come to light,
لكي تظهر هذه التفاصيل على السطح،
and I realized that there was no natural animosity
وأدركت أنه ليس هناك أي عداء طبيعي
between the two of us.
بيننا نحن الاثنين.
I had never had a Jewish friend before,
لم يكن لي صديق يهودي من قبل،
and frankly I felt a sense of pride
وبصراحة أحسست بالفخر
in having been able to overcome a barrier
أنني استطعت تجاوز عقبة
that for most of my life I had been led to believe
كنت قد حُمِلتُ طوال حياتي على تصديق
was insurmountable.
أنه من المستحيل تجاوزها.
Another major turning point came when
نقطة تحول كبرى حدثت حين
I found a summer job at Busch Gardens,
وجدت عملا صيفيا في "بوش غاردنز"،
an amusement park.
وهي حديقة ترفيهية.
There, I was exposed to people from all sorts of faiths and cultures,
هناك، التقيت بأشخاص من مختلف المعتقدات والثقافات،
and that experience proved to be fundamental
وتبين أن تلك التجربة كانت أساسية
to the development of my character.
في تطور شخصيتي.
Most of my life, I'd been taught
طوال معظم حياتي، قيل لي
that homosexuality was a sin, and by extension,
أن المثلية الجنسية هي ذنب، وبالتالي،
that all gay people were a negative influence.
أن كل الناس المثليين لهم تأثير سلبي.
As chance would have it, I had the opportunity
وقد صادف، أن أتيحت لي الفرصة
to work with some of the gay performers
للعمل مع ممثلين مثليين
at a show there,
في عرض هناك،
and soon found that many were the kindest,
وبعدها بقليل اكتشفت أن بعضا منهم كانوا من ألطف،
least judgmental people I had ever met.
وأقل الناس حكما على الآخرين.
Being bullied as a kid
كوني تعرضت للمضايقات عندما كنت طفلا
created a sense of empathy in me
خلق فيَّ نوعا من التعاطف
toward the suffering of others,
مع معاناة الآخرين،
and it comes very unnaturally to me
ويبدو لي من غير الطبيعي بتاتا
to treat people who are kind
أن أعامل الناس اللطفاء
in any other way than how I would want to be treated.
بأي طريقة أخرى غير التي أحب أن أُعامل بها.
Because of that feeling, I was able
وبفضل ذلك الشعور،كنت قادرا
to contrast the stereotypes I'd been taught as a child
على مقارنة الصور النمطية التي تلقيتها عندما كنت طفلا
with real life experience and interaction.
مع التجربة الحياتية الحقيقة والتعامل مع الناس.
I don't know what it's like to be gay,
لا أدري مالذي يعنيه أن تكون شاذا جنسيا،
but I'm well acquainted with being judged
لكنني أعلم جيدا ما الذي يعنيه أن يُحكَم عليّ
for something that's beyond my control.
بخصوص شيء خارج عن إرادتي.
Then there was "The Daily Show."
بعدها جاء برنامج "ذ دايلي شو."
On a nightly basis, Jon Stewart forced me
فكان جون ستيوارت يجبرني، كل ليلة
to be intellectually honest with myself about my own bigotry
على أن أكون صادقا فكريا مع نفسي بخصوص تعصبي
and helped me to realize that a person's race,
وساعدني لكي أدرك أنه لا علاقة لعرق المرء
religion or sexual orientation
أو دينه أو توجهه الجنسي
had nothing to do with the quality of one's character.
بنوعية شخصيته.
He was in many ways a father figure to me
كان في بعض الأحيان يشكل شخصية الأب بالنسبة لي
when I was in desperate need of one.
حين كنت في أمس الحاجة للأب.
Inspiration can often come from an unexpected place,
يمكن للإلهام أن يأتي من مكان غير متوقع،
and the fact that a Jewish comedian had done more
وكون كوميدي يهودي قد قام بالكثير
to positively influence my worldview
ليؤثر إيجابا على رؤيتي للعالم
than my own extremist father
أكثر مما فعل والدي المتطرف
is not lost on me.
فإني لا أعد هذا خسارة بالنسبة لي.
One day, I had a conversation with my mother
ذات يوم، كنت أتحدث إلى والدتي
about how my worldview was starting to change,
عن أن نظرتي للعالم قد بدأت تتغير،
and she said something to me
فقالت لي أمرا
that I will hold dear to my heart
سأظل أحمله دائما في قلبي
for as long as I live.
طالما حييت.
She looked at me with the weary eyes
نظرت إلى بعينين متعبتين
of someone who had experienced
يحملهما من جرّب
enough dogmatism to last a lifetime, and said,
الدغمائية بما فيه الكفاية في حياته، وقالت،
"I'm tired of hating people."
"لقد تعبت من كراهية الناس."
In that instant, I realized how much negative energy
في تلك اللحظة، أدركت كمية الطاقة السلبية
it takes to hold that hatred inside of you.
التي يتطلبها حمل تلك الكراهية بداخلك.
Zak Ebrahim is not my real name.
زاك إبراهيم ليس اسمي الحقيقي.
I changed it when my family decided
غيرته حين قررت عائلتي
to end our connection with my father
أن تقطع صلتها بوالدي
and start a new life.
وبدء حياة جديدة.
So why would I out myself
إذن فلم أخرج إلى العلن
and potentially put myself in danger?
وأضع نفسي في موضع خطر محتمل؟
Well, that's simple.
حسنا، الأمر بسيط.
I do it in the hopes that perhaps someone someday
أقوم بهذا على أمل أنه ربما يكون هناك شخص ما يوما ما
who is compelled to use violence
مجبرا على استعمال العنف
may hear my story and realize
ربما قد يستمع إلى قصتي ويدرك
that there is a better way,
أن هناك طريقا أفضل،
that although I had been subjected
أنه وإن كنت عرضة
to this violent, intolerant ideology,
لذلك العنف، والإيديولوجية غير المتسامحة،
that I did not become fanaticized.
لم أصبح متعصبا.
Instead, I choose to use my experience
عوضا عن ذلك، اخترت أن أستعمل تجربتي
to fight back against terrorism,
لأحارب ضد الإرهاب،
against the bigotry.
ضد التعصب.
I do it for the victims of terrorism
أقوم بهذا من أجل ضحايا الإرهاب
and their loved ones,
وأحبائهم،
for the terrible pain and loss
والألم والخسارة الأليمة
that terrorism has forced upon their lives.
التي أجبرهم الإرهاب على عيشها.
For the victims of terrorism, I will speak out
لضحايا الإرهاب، سأتحدث بصوت عال
against these senseless acts
ضد هذه الأعمال الخرقاء
and condemn my father's actions.
وأدين ما قام به والدي.
And with that simple fact, I stand here as proof
وببساطة، أقف هنا كدليل
that violence isn't inherent in one's religion or race,
أن العنف ليس متأصلا في دين أو عرق المرء،
and the son does not have to follow
وأنه ليس على الابن أن يتبع
the ways of his father.
خطى والده.
I am not my father.
أنا لست أبي.
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا لكم. (تصفيق)
Thank you, everybody. (Applause)
شكرا لكم، جميعا. (تصفيق)
Thanks a lot. (Applause)
شكرا جزيلا. (تصفيق)